is starting uh and so recording has
started. I am admitting everybody from
the lobby and so good afternoon
everybody. Uh we are admitting everyone
from the lobby as most of you know since
it looks like everybody who's on the the
attendees list are people who have
joined before. It does take a minute or
two for people to all join in. Um in the
meantime uh since the meeting has
started we are recording. So, as a
reminder, please remember to keep
language to be appropriate uh simply
because we do post these on up and we
want to ensure that it is available for
people of all ages. Um and uh it looks
like we have everybody uh in the waiting
room is now joined in. So, um, just as a
reminder, this is the equity, access,
and cultural consideration committee
meeting for today, August 18th. My name
is Dr. Dominic Zerlo, and I am here uh,
from the New Mexico Department of
Health. Uh, this meeting is chaired by
Dezba and, uh, so I will turn it on over
to Dezba.
Thank you everybody for joining.
>> Uh, y a uh, thank you everyone for
joining us today. um we had a possible
presentation, but we will see how things
look at 4 um to see if we're going to
get that presentation. Um in the
meantime, we do have one of our advisory
board members who did um come up with a
presentation. So we'll or you know not a
presentation but some interesting
information that would be possible to
present in lie of this other
presentation that we were hoping to
have. Um that one was going to be on
tribal sovereignty outreach uh
recommendations and um potential
um looking into that. Um on that note um
I was able to for those who were not in
the um advisory board meeting was it
Friday um I gave an update for this uh
equity access and cultural
considerations uh uh committee that I
was actually able to make some contact
um with the help of the department of
health's tribal leaison um to meet with
some uh tribal leaders in healthcare
there um to be able to just kind of uh
start making progress towards bridging
that understanding um towards
uh again tribal sovereignty and how the
tribes that are here in New Mexico would
like to be involved or proceed in coming
up with um a collaborative effort of
recommendations that would best meet the
needs of their own people. recognizing
that not only are we a part of New
Mexico that you know we're citizens of
New Mexico as a state within the United
States, but we are also uh this land and
these borders are home to uh tribal
entities that have their own sovereignty
and are essentially treated as their own
countries um within the state and within
the United States. Um so that has been
one of our priorities. Um, but as anyone
who has worked with anyone else, um,
sometimes these things take time and
it's not just a matter of like knocking
on someone's door. Um, you know, this
has been a long-standing interest for
many people. Um, if anyone hasn't been
following um the, uh, the journey of the
journey of the psilocybin um, process
within the United States, you know, we
had Oregon, we had Colorado, and now
we're in New Mexico. Hopefully, we're
going to be getting some more states
that um are involving and or basing
their uh programs through uh traditional
ancestral indigenous wisdom. Um we have
hopefully Alaska, which is going to be
moving forward with theirs hopefully at
some point. But I feel like New Mexico
is is able to to do something different
that hasn't been done before, which is
really base our program in the
understanding that we are not just New
Mexico citizens. That this is a land
that has been um inhabited by people for
tens of thousands of years. in that
language, in that um place here in this
land is very important to understanding
how we approach the medicine and to our
people here as well as anyone who is
coming to live within the borders of New
Mexico. Um with that said, um I wouldn't
mind if people who would like to
introduce themselves introduce
themselves. I think I see a few new
people here. um if you wouldn't mind
either um
raising your hand to introduce yourself
and or if you feel more comfortable just
saying hi in the chat if you please do
so that would be great
nobody
>> Ian
everyone um my name is Ian Dunn I am a
medical psilocybin advisory board member
I just wanted to Um, I'm definitely no
expert on tribal sovereignty, but to
recognize that the tribal sovereignty
outdates the United States, the state of
New Mexico, um, even, you know, New
Spain and all of that. So, getting a
chance to hear their perspectives and to
make sure that they have a seat at the
table is very important. I definitely
think that they have an very important
intersection, especially when it comes
to integration. Um so if you look at the
circle of care um integration is not
just specifically therapy it can be you
know physical mental behavioral health
practices and um given Medicaid's
historical or historic coverage for
traditional healing practices. Um I
think this is a great time to work on
integration within that aspect. Um and
thank all of the perspectives for being
here. Yeah. Thank you.
Hanifa.
>> Hi. Good afternoon. Can you hear me?
>> Mhm.
>> Okay. Wonderful. Hey everyone. So, I'm
Hana Washington. I'm a new resident of
New Mexico. I live in Santa Fe. Been
here for about a year and have been
spending time in New Mexico with
regularity for about three years. um
working to uh support the development of
um the UNM study that is has launched um
for PTSD working closely with Dr. Leman
um and you know many several therapists
uh throughout the state and the
[clears throat] study is really not only
looking at the advocacy of psilocybin
therapy on PTSD but it's also looking at
the the model right so we're looking at
group care models and also what it what
it means to move through um
[clears throat]
a psychedelic assisted therapy protocol
with an affinity group. So, the study
focuses on um veterans and first
responders, women survivors of sexual
trauma, and tribal and indigenous um
community members here in New Mexico. Um
so, really trying to show um the
advocacy of group work and what it means
to move through that work in an affinity
group. So, people who have the same
lived experience. Um, and
[clears throat] we're doing these
studies across the country to support
building data and evidence that shows
the effectiveness of that model,
particularly when it comes to under
reppresented folks and folks who are
underserved. Um, and I'm really happy uh
to be here today and excited for the
presentation later. Thank you.
>> Thank you, Heneife. Any uh Chris?
>> Hi, Des. I am Chris Dusky. I'm a veteran
and a advisory board member and uh
facilitator for the same GPAT study that
Heneifeh has been working so hard on for
so long [snorts] and um just here to
support the process and to support this.
Thank you.
>> All right. Thank you. We also have Don
Moser in the chat from Las Vegas. Okay.
Um let's see.
uh sort of recap. I think that we have
most people, everybody that's been here,
there might be like I said a couple of
people. We The goal that we've been
having is what to do with $630,000
of our equity fund that is available. It
is a non-reverting fund, meaning the
money that's there is not going to be
sucked back into the government and put
into the big pool of money. Those are my
words. [laughter]
Um but essentially it is it is there for
us to use as of last month in July. So
we have from now until through the rest
of the program um uh starting December
31st at the end of this year um to be
able to allocate um the funds in a way
that would be most beneficial to
um the people of New Mexico. $630,000
is not a lot of money. We're thankful
and grateful that we did we were able to
get this money, but for those of you
that that sometimes may or may not be
able to buy a house here in Santa Fe. So
that isn't necessarily a lot of money,
but it is definitely a lot of money to
be able to figure out how we can um
utilize it so that the most number of
people that it can be effective towards
um who are presenting with um the
prescribed
uh presenting
uh health mental health issues that this
might be better uh suited for. the best
best suited for with the best outcomes
and trying to put all these different
pieces together when it comes to uh
training, research, data collection. Um
how we're going to be able to use
Medicaid, any other types of of programs
that might be able to uh cut the cost of
this particular um medicine. We there
are a lot of variables that we still
don't know yet. how much a um a dose
would cost, how much a session will
cost, how many sessions will be
available um and you know assigning
essentially triaging my again my words
of like who would be best suited for
this medicine across the two million um
members of New Mexico who might be able
to apply for these types of assistance.
There's a lot of variables we still
haven't quite got through. But the whole
point of it is is to put our brains
together to figure out a method and or a
way that we're not only getting to rural
areas to the most um needed places um
that it's not just completely allocated
say to Santa Fe or Albuquerque, Los
Cusus or any of the bigger cities. and
how we're going to be able to get that
word out, the education out so that
people know that this is an option and
it is available. Um, so there's again a
lot of different factors that we're
trying to be able to help send
recommendations to the board which will
then recommend to the department of
health and then therefore the department
of health will then come up with
regulations and best practices that um
will still be able to be um uh moved
around even after voting and deciding on
them. So, with that, um, like I said, we
were going to have a presentation on
tribal sovereignty. Hopefully, we'll be
able to get that in at 4. If not, we
will, um, make that available hopefully
in September or the next meeting that we
have. Um, but for now, we get to have,
uh, Ian, who is our chair of our
advisory board, um, would like to give a
little information on some insights that
he threw together. Um and so Ian, would
you mind however you choose to discuss
whether
if you're ready?
>> Yeah. So um hi everyone, my name is Ian.
So yeah, I just wanted to kind of lay
out how we could potentially spend this
um money, how we could best allocate it.
And so the fund is actually divided into
two separate funds. It is the medical
psilocybin treatment fund that has um
$150,000 in it. And then there's the
psilocybin access fund which has
$480,000.
So what I'm thinking and let's see if my
computer will actually allow me to share
my screen. Sometimes it's nice. Um
cool. Can you see that?
>> We can see it now.
>> Cool.
Um, Dominic, did you want to say
something first before?
>> No, I was just I was just trying to do a
thumbs up to let you know that it was
showing.
>> Okay, great.
>> Cool. Um, so these are not final numbers
by any means. They were just let's get
us started kind of discussing what we
can do. So the first idea I had was um
for those initial patients, right, the
economies of scale are going to favor
big cities, not necessarily for what
we're providing funds for, just for what
people um
have from them. So for instance, um that
the population of Albuquerque can
support um more healing centers off the
bat than for instance Gallup or other
rural communities. So it would be the
psilocybin travel reserve where we would
provide reimbursement to qualified
patients whose residence is more than 50
driving miles from the treatment center.
We would use NMDFA mileage and pdium
rates and include reasonable lodging
expenses when overnight um recovery is
required. Then we could also work with
rural and underserved area grants. Um,
so we would provide $10,000
grants to qualifying new healing centers
located in rural or underserved areas.
Um, so the eligibility would be right no
qualified healing center within 50 mi.
Center must be newly established. Center
must remain operational for at least 3
years. Center must accept qualified
patients for receiving psilocybin
treatment equity fund assistance. Um and
the center must meet minimum annual
patient service requirement determined
by the department depending on how much
demand there is. Right. Um we would
forgive the grant after 3 years of
qualifying operation. A recipient of the
grant under this section shouldn't
impose additional treatment charges. Um
if a patient is using the psilocybin
treatment equity fund. So I just don't
want you know them to hear, oh the
government's paying, so we're just going
to charge them more. Um, next area where
we could really support these areas is
with loans. Given that we don't have
very much money in this um, book, it
would allow us to provide very low
interest. I was thinking somewhere
between 0 and 5% um, of up to $50,000 to
qualifying new healing centers. We would
keep that low interest. We would give
them 5 years. We would know give them no
prepayment penalty. Um if they are in a
rural and underserved area, which I
described as saying no one within 50
driving miles. Um must accept qualified
patients receiving the equity fund and
must remain operational during the loan
term. Um unused principal returned to
the fund is relo to subsequent
qualifying applicants. A recipient of a
loan under this section shouldn't impose
additional treatment charges for people.
And then um access contingency reserve.
So that would be if someone was already
getting equity assistance and they
needed emergency patient transportation,
exceptional lodging expenses,
accessibility accommodations, or rural
areas within the 15 mile criterion
produces an inequitable result. So if
you were right on the border from two
that are 50 mi away, you shouldn't be
penalized and still have to drive that
um distance. And then the next area or
the other fund would just be the
treatment fund. Um that is for direct
treatment vouchers. Um we would use a
standard eligibility scale. So this is
in dark and it does not
look as well.
Sorry for blinding everyone. But um we
would provide direct treatment vouchers
for the first 100,000 and then 50,000
for patient preparation and integration.
This is still operating under the
assumption that the direct
administration of psilocybin cannot be
covered but um therapy and other
approved services outside that could be
for preparation or integration would be
covered. Um that's how it's broken up
currently but again we are still waiting
for final confirmation from HCA. So
these are just ideas they are not
finalized in thought. I just wanted to
give us a starting place to for
discussion. So I will open it to the
floor the committee um see what you guys
think and yeah.
>> Thank you Ann. Um, is there anybody that
wants to start off asking any questions
or I see that um is that Senator
Seinborn in there? Yes.
Go ahead, Jeff.
>> Thanks. I'm stepping out of an office
right now. I'll be able to talk to you
guys. Thanks for your ideas. It's really
interesting. Um, I wanted to share a
little little info. Um, so it's kind of
interesting. the money. The reason Ann
is it it shows up as like separate funds
was just almost the drafters didn't
catch it because there were individual
legislators who use some of their
discretionary funding capacity. They
submitted it and the drafter usually
they consolidate them and they just kind
of there I think it ended up on a
multiple line items. So it might be
written slightly different but the 630
is all for the equity treatment fund. In
law there's only two funds. One is for
the E equity treatment fund. The other
is for research, which we've never
actually put money into that fund
because we've chosen instead to give the
money directly to UNM to accelerate
research rather than have to go through
government RFP process. But um
so on the equity fund, your ideas of
helping healing centers are interesting,
but I would flag a couple things. one
that
so it kind of create it would have a
programmatic creation would have to be
funded and uh
and so that's that would spend money
that's not appropriated right now to the
department and that I don't know
necessarily that you want the fund being
used for the other thought justeneral
generally speaking is I think if we give
money directly for patient care then
that's going to help all the healing
centers that's going to help everyone in
the space because they're going to have
a revenue stream so that's the way that
we help them in a way this this will
help them um I think the law really
doesn't allow for us to help them
separate from treating patients I think
that would probably go be coloring
outside the bound pounds of what the law
says about the equity fund. So, but I
like the concept. Um, I think probably
simpler would be better, but I, you
know, I've always been worried about
guard rails of making sure that you
don't have a couple practitioners in one
field just suddenly make a run on the
fund and if there aren't any rules to
say no, then all the money could go to
just one practice wherever it is in the
state. So that's where I do like the
idea of creating a few guard rails. But
um how I would recommend that I you know
I don't have much doubt other than I
think I suggested before doing it by
maybe qualified condition or you could
even set set do some geographic you know
no more than you know x amount
um
you know I don't know I'm just
spitballing but anyway I'll stop right
there. I just wanted to kind of give my
my first feedback, but I'd love to look
at your your plan in depth later, Ken.
Thanks, guys.
>> That um yeah, no, I was going off of the
separate line items in the actual bill.
So, if they are all for patient equity,
then we can just focus on this second
part. Um which is based on the federal
poverty line, 200% phases out by 300%.
Um and then Heneife had another
question.
Honey. Hey.
>> Okay. Thanks. Um [clears throat] I'm
curious if anyone from the department
can give an update on what is the plan
for confirming with HCA
their their what they will be covering.
Um because so much is hinging on that
and do we just are going to just
continue to assume or do we have a plan
for actually figuring out when they will
determine that those factors?
Thank you. Uh
>> good afternoon, Heneifeha, and everybody
on here. Uh that's actually up to HCA
and we have requested and my
understanding is that they're working
through that. It's not as simple as it
may sound where they just would, you
know, say we're going to pay for these
these portions. They also have to figure
out where that funding will come from
themselves, how that will be done. uh
will it be something that will be
eligible on the federal level or will it
have to just be state monies and so
going through that and I know they've
been working through all of that and
through those issues. So when exactly
we'll know, we do not know either, but
we have been in regular communication
and as you all or at least most of you
know they've had their board member
representative either uh Alana Dances or
Kenan Ryan who has been there and uh in
the meeting last Friday they said they
were still working on it as to exactly
what would be able to be covered but no
we do not have an answer yet.
>> Okay, thank you for that. Um, and I just
wonder like is it the exercise is it
worth doing the exercise of creating,
you know, the two plans. One that says
this is contingent on the assumption
that they will cover and then one that's
like they're not covering or should we
just just hope that they come through? I
guess I'm curious around the timeline of
when we need to put forward
recommendations around this.
Yeah, I think didn't we say that this
was going to be next up on the docket
after um the training and education?
>> Yes, it it it is Desba. Um but um if we
do want to have this in place or at
least a plan in place, um we do need to
do something sooner rather than later.
um what um a as far as making two
separate plans, I wouldn't actually
recommend that because the issue is
about what individual's needs are, not
necessarily what may be end up being
paid elsewhere. So if um HCA is able to
pay uh out of Medicaid andor other
insurers are able to pay, then that's
not going to change what necessarily
what the need is. It might shift where
that need is in some cases, but it's not
really going to necessarily change the
need. And we know no matter what that
HCA is not going Medicaid and the
insurers are not going to pay for some
parts of it. For example, they're not
going to pay for the actual
administration or for the medication
itself. So, what I would really
recommend is to create one plan. The
real question is going to end up being,
you know, how many people will able to
be be able to benefit from it. And
that's what's really going to depend
upon whether those other third parties
are able to pay for different portions.
>> Yeah. So, I'm I mean I I've been joking
about it, but I'm actually very serious
when I say we need a mathematician.
There's a reason why we have
mathematicians looking at E= MC^2. We
know the constant is the uh how the
speed of light it's traveling. But when
you have these different variables, A +
B + C divided by whatever whatever
whatever it's basically all based on
these multiple variables. And once you
get one piece of the puzzle, you can
plug it in so that then that will
affect, you know, the other part of it
to create whatever that formula is. And
it really does sound like that's
essentially what's trying to happen
here. And a little bit to Dominic's
point of like, you know, coming up with
like a plan, you know, not multiple
plans is just figuring out what is that
formula going to look like um to be able
to then equal 600. like we the the one
constant we do know is the $630,000.
That is the equals on the other side of
the equal sign. Then we got to be able
to figure out what is on the other side
of that equal sign um based on the
number of applicants, based on um you
know the cost of the sessions, the cost
of the medicine. Then we have you know
what would be another variable is the
HCA. I'm not sure if that is including
Medicaid, but we're looking at at least
probably 10 different types of variables
in here that we don't know what they
are. And I and I totally understand that
that is very very frustrating. But I do
not think that that means we cannot come
up with the types of variables that will
be on the other side of that equal sign
to see the things that we're going to
have to look at. Um, and maybe that just
sounds like duh. I don't know. Um, but
I'm just if if that's the duh moment for
someone, at least that's what I'm
reiterating back that I'm hearing is
that we we need to figure out what those
what A equals, what B equals C and there
and all the way down that way. Um in
[clears throat]
>> yeah I just um so then in regard to this
what we can do is just look at the
equity fund on direct treatment
vouchers. That would be the part we know
Medicaid is not going to cover. Um we
can still tie it to federal poverty
line. I think we agreed to that at last
session. I just don't think we did
specific numbers.
The problem is is that we will not know
until we start receiving patient
applications how many to expect. So I
think at least this is a good starting
place and then we can obviously
prioritize by need um and by how
um how much like people need and how
much um
patients we end up having. We don't
really have good
statistics on
our qualifi like we don't know an exact
number of how many patients are going to
be eligible on day one. Nor do we know
how many are going to want to
participate. Um cuz just because they're
eligible doesn't mean they'll want to
participate. So I think we have to just
take almost a leap and say here's what
we can provide. Note, this money only
has to last for 6 months from January to
through June.
Um,
and then hopefully we'll have a good
pilot program to show here's what we
need for fiscal year 27 or 28. I don't
know how they're labeled, but um yeah,
but you understand the gist. Yeah, I
think I think again back to if we figure
out what it is that is potentially being
covered like what is the minus, what is
the subtraction, right? Are we
subtracting the HCA? And forgive me, I
would love correction, but are we
subtracting HCA? Are we uh subtracting
Medicaid? What other potential
um you know, I don't want to say known,
right? It could be zero. It could
totally be zero, but any other known
possibilities of subtracting from that,
right? So, a negative would be um HCA, a
negative would be Medicaid costs, right?
Um it might also be the non-silocybin
uh non-silicon sessions that are also
involved in this. That would also be um
potentially something that is being
subtracted from it. It could also be
something that is being added to it. I
don't know. Um, again, I just, this
might be confusing for some people, but
this was just a brainstorming that I was
thinking about. You know, if we're
actually looking at, right, heroes
doses, whether it's like one gram or uh,
is it gram? Yeah. One gram versus three
grams, four grams, like what is the
average? If it's three grams, you know,
what is that actually really? What are
we looking at? I think I was throwing
around this number of like four pounds
four pounds of of psilocybin which
doesn't seem like a lot and at the same
time it is. [laughter]
It's a lot. Um I think that the number
came up I can't remember what the
numbers are. If someone wants to do the
math that would be great. Um but four
pounds of psilocybin at three grams per
dose is like I think a thousand or some
maybe it's 150ome people. I don't know.
But divided that into $630,000. It's
like, you know, all these types of
numbers and how many people then that
also kind of puts into, well, if you
only really need four pounds of
psilocybin for the program, that's also
not a lot to grow. That's that's easy to
grow. And like one person could
potentially grow all of that. One
company, one one distributor, one
cultivator. Um, which then also brings
in other variables which you know could
be something to be considered. Um,
whether or not uh, you know, are we are
we going to be favoring smaller
practices, bigger practices, people who
have more access to the training, less
access to the training, whether or not
this is going to affect the rural
communities and how we're going to do
that. Um, so I feel like if we were able
to at least pin down what these
different variables are like a equals
number of applicants, then we have the
number of detractors minus the Medicaid
minus the HCA. Then if we have a
timeline that we're going to have this
divided over the number of months are we
going to are we going to see you know a
speed a peak or valleys of the number of
applicants for you know a given time are
we dividing up the state between
counties um
yeah it just it to me seems like very
comp I've never had to figure out this
kind of word problem before I I would
assume that the department of health has
plenty of experience in figuring this
out. But these are all the ideas and
thoughts that I'm that it's it's it's
coming to as far as like the things that
might need to be um considered. Um but I
think that some potential concerns might
be just the cost that ends up
snowballing with the price of the
psilocybin itself. Um where it's coming
from. um all these added because if
we're going to be making and I think
this is what Senator Steinborn was
saying it's not to the facilities
themselves essentially but what is the
um the through line from essentially the
journey of the psilocybin from
cultivator to testing to facilitator to
um whoever else is handling right the
time that it takes for the psilocybin to
get to the actual person All of that
costs money. Someone asked one time like
what is why are you talking about um
travel costs? Well, I'm talking about
the travel costs of the psilocybin, the
psilocybin's journey from you know spore
essentially to ingestion of the person
and that care of that person. That's the
travel that I'm talking about. And each
stop adds on and tacks on another uh
dollar mark, right? But then once that
is little snowballs sport is being
tacked on with all this much more money
then we're going to figure out what is
being what is being paid for in that
sense which is where the Medicaid and
the HCA and any other entity that might
be able to cut down the cost of that
medicine to the actual person when it
gets delivered.
Um
I just rambled a lot. Um I'm sorry. So
um um our presenter was not going to be
able to present today um with the tribal
sovereignty uh presentation. Um it was
done in conjunction
um to best practices essentially for um
since this is this is a very big
committee which is equity, access and
cultural considerations meaning not only
is it have to deal with money um and
financial but also how this essentially
to me education is being disseminated
not only to citizens of New Mexico but
again specifically to tribal sovereignty
um federally recognized uh citizens. Um
and with that I've completely lost him.
Does anyone else have any questions or
thoughts or
um
Thank you, Ian, for um creating this
little graph and kind of coming up with
these other um potential ideas for uh
for Yeah.
Anybody else?
Let's see.
Okay. [clears throat]
chat here.
Okay.
>> Yeah. Did I just lose everybody?
>> No, people are here. [laughter]
>> Jeff,
it's you know I have a thought which is
right now we know we have 630,000.
We don't know how long it has to last.
We have to kind of treat it as if it's
the only 630 we're ever going to have
for years. I mean, you never know. I've
been in the legislature when we go from
a record surplus to suddenly a pandemic
hits, oil prices go through the floor,
six months later, literally we're not
only we're dealing with budget deficits
and we have to cut things and there's no
opportunity to appropriate new money.
Um, in fact, when those cycles hit, they
hit unexpected and they hit quick. And I
saw this in 2008 when Richardson was we
literally just given a tax cut with like
surplus money and people were like, I
don't know. And then 6 months later, we
were literally in a deficit with the uh
global economy and you know, you
remember the great recession of 2008. So
the truth is is is we're sitting good
now but we you know we have to plan as
if with a little bit of frugality and so
having said that we are heading into a
session I think there's some of us who
are definitely going to try to secure
more funding we have a lot of funding
needs for the program I will say that
are first order of magnitude priority
like funding the department of health
itself data some other stuff the equity
fund is definitely on that
But uh but I say this from the
standpoint of
we don't have to over complicate it
either like like you know if you go into
a lot of complexity as if you're
creating this architecture for a
long-term plan the fact is is the
numbers are going to change the math is
going to change once we see demand
that's going to change and I think maybe
for right now keeping it at a reasonable
poverty level is the fair way to do it
that treats everybody the same based on
income and And
you know some minimum safeguards
personally I would love to see that just
so we protect broad use of it um
geographically but beyond that you know
I would advise don't don't let's not I
don't know we don't necessarily need to
overly complicate it because things are
going to change within the next six
months and part of that change may be us
getting more money in which case that
changes things and some of the question
with HCA becomes clear. So it's just
things are going to change and for now
keeping it simple, streamlined,
you know, a few smart things built into
it, I think is a good path forward
because you're right, Dezbot, we could
go there's so many considerations like
you could take this to a level of
granularity that could really make your
head spin. But uh
I think just of course the purpose of
the fund is to just help people with
limited means who couldn't afford this
otherwise get that treatment and that's
in its simplest form what we can do. So
that'd be my kind of thought just
looking at things 30,000 ft and also
knowing what could happen in the
legislative session and all other
factors. We're just things are going to
change. things are definitely going to
change and and if you keep with
something simple, it may be perfect.
They just be elegant and perfect and
serve us no matter what those changes
are too. But so just wanted to share
that perspective.
>> Thank you, Senator. And I think I I mean
it definitely is is a seemingly as
simple just you know help everybody that
you know asks which is simp is which is
as simple as saying you know any pan
handler that you see out on you know you
you give everybody money but I think
part of like the question that people
don't want to ask and it's and it's
we're trying to and then also it's just
hard to it's like I mean I hear it all
the time and I'm using that as an
example because people are like don't
give to them. Don't give to them because
you don't know what they're going to use
it for, etc. So, it comes into this idea
um that
uh
like how how is it that we're going to
know
who is of the most need? Then it comes
into um
um
the the other conversations that we're
having about
part of the regulations that are already
in place. We have screening for this. We
have di diagnostician stools tools that
will decide who will get this and who
will not. which then comes into
question. If we have if someone has more
access and it usually does happen in a
bigger city then they may have more
access to getting that diagnosis
than someone else in a rural place. I
will give an example. I specifically
purposely moved my family here to Santa
Fe and you know there's also people
always say you know to go to Los Alamos
because they have the better schools.
Go to Albuquerque if you want more
variety but I chose to move here to
Santa Fe. I grew up in Rioipa.
Um so when you have more access to
something
because it is provided because usually
generally that happens with a bigger
city you're leaving behind the rural
areas and I think that is like the
bigger concern for everyone. It's not so
much that we don't have the heart to
help everybody, but how how is that
being done? Because especially everyone
knows again the bigger cities are going
to have like a greater advantage and how
do we mitigate that that we are not
leaving the people behind that we feel
that the whole state two million people
if they wanted to if every single person
in in New Mexico wanted to have access
to this um how are we going to decide of
those two million people which are the
which are the absolute top priority of
of uh for that $630,000.
And maybe it is the majority of the
people are here in Santa Fe. Maybe it is
the majority of the people who need it
are in Albuquerque, but I don't think
that's true. I mean, maybe people in
Farmington or Roswell or Clovis or
Prales or anywhere else don't feel like
they need it. Um maybe they don't even
know that it's an option. That's another
thing. Um, so while I hear that it's,
you know, very simple to just help as
many people as possible and the people
who need it most, but how how is the
question? Um, let's see. I think I Ian,
you had your hand up first.
>> Yes. So, I think it's the um Socratic
principle of true knowledge is knowing
you know, you know nothing. And so we're
not going to know all of the answers,
but I do agree with Senator Steinborn
that
federal poverty level and income is one
of the more accurate and not accurate
but fair ways to distribute that income.
Um because it it directly deals with the
resources that a family has. Um it's not
perfect. Um no system is. But one way we
could help in the same aspect is by
reimbursing for maybe if they do have to
travel a long time to a treatment center
um or things like that to just help
equalize. We don't want more people in
like urban areas to be overly
advantaged. Um, but I think that income
is a way that we can at least try to be
fair with, of course, safeguards
>> Dominic.
>> Yeah, good afternoon everybody. Um, I'm
putting this in the chat. This is these
are items that we've actually uh made as
potential uh recommendations throughout
the last oh, I think it's we've met like
10 or 12 times. Um, and there are
different things that have come on up
and it's uh some of these are items that
are very simple seeming but actually do
a lot of what everybody has been talking
about and so I've put it in the chat and
essentially what we're talking about is
that we would look at the fund covering
for individuals who are at or below 200%
of the poverty level that the items that
would be covered would be that
diagnostic evaluation. So those that
appointment or necessarily appointments
because it may may be more than one for
that diagnostic evaluation medical
clearance up to two preparatory sessions
the administration day itself up to four
integrative sessions after the
administration day and the cost of the
medication. And in addition to be able
to help in those more rural uh areas,
travel if the patient resides more than
a 100 miles from the appointment uh
location or healing center. So that
would include the diagnostic
evaluations, uh preparatory sessions in
person, etc. Um and then the fund itself
would end up being the last payer. So it
would be required that the providers
attempt to get paid by Medicaid,
insurers, etc. first and then reimburse
through the fund if that did not happen.
Now the exception of course on that is
uh we would look at in some cases people
do have the ability to get their travel
reimbursed other times they don't. So we
would we could put in a provision that
ensures if travel is not a part of what
they would be able to pay for that could
be reimbursed to the patient a lot
quicker and right away. And then of
course from a reimbursement standpoint
is that it would not exceed the rates
that we currently have for Medicaid
reimbursement. That helps to keep the
costs to a more reasonable level and
helps to reduce that overall from a
state and it would be what the state
already would be paying if somebody did
have that coverage for Medicaid. Um, of
course the one piece that wouldn't be
there and that we would want to put in
is a a maximum cost on the medication.
And what I would recommend really on
that is that the department make a
determination of that once we have the
producers and that we do that based on
some sort of a formula based upon how
much it costs for them to produce the
medication and what the reasonable cost
would be. We might be able to even do it
as an average cost of the medication,
but that we could get that determination
figured out at that time. the actual fee
schedule doesn't need to go into the
regulations and so that would be
something that we could create and have
that mechanism and so what the other
piece of this is because there are so
many unknowns is this makes it at least
I think makes it fair across the board
allows for the ability of people who are
have issues with regard to travel and
things like that to be able to cover it.
Um uh and and by the way when I say
travel that also potentially includes
travel of a provider to the patient if
for example that patient is homebound
for whatever reason. So it's not just
travel of the patient also potentially
travel of provider. um and that this we
think this would make this actually a
lot more reasonable. And quite frankly,
um it wouldn't be that difficult to
write this up into the portions needed
for regulations. And then what the
department would commit to because we're
already need to do this anyway based
upon the bill is to gather the
information, the demographics, the
information on it over the next year to
two years, etc. to be able to determine
do how do we need to refine this? How do
we make this so that it is a little bit
more fair in other ways and in other um
you know other areas to ensure are we
actually through this reaching those
more rural frontier areas? Are we
reaching people who are living on
sovereign land? Are we reaching the
individuals we need to? But this gives
us that start and it starts by us being
able to actually help treat patients and
also to be able to gather the data that
nobody has and nobody knows right now.
So I I actually would like to to propose
if it's okay with this committee that we
move forward with this kind of a
recommendation because it would allow us
to be able to start moving forward from
a regulatory side in creating this and
getting things moving.
Definitely. Um I would re Thank you so
much uh Dominic for um putting that in
there and uh I I think so. But let me
hear from Chris
>> and Jeff. [clears throat]
Um, so first of all, I think having up
to two preparatory sessions is not
necessarily and up to four integrative
sessions. It just seems
um like maybe we should put up in
something like up to six sessions that
could be used for either of those things
more likely
especially I think
um
dealing with people in lower income
brackets because to live in poverty is
to live in chaos like it might take a
little bit more prep to get them ready
for this. Um and then
four integrative sessions
[snorts]
seems like it might be a lot for one
journey and one journey
you know you it might take several
sessions to to find the right dose to
get people where they need to be. So I'm
not I'm not sure if [clears throat]
I agree with the this structure of it.
Um
so those would be my recommendations is
put up to six sessions and how those are
split up between preparation and
integration
um to properly get them ready for the
journey
uh would make more sense to me. And then
um putting in options for maybe up to
three administration sessions might uh
be more valuable than having one session
that may have limited results just
because you don't have proper dosage and
they don't really have a journey.
>> Thank thank you Chris. And just on that
I I don't think it's an issue. It was
more of a you know looking at it in the
different uh sections. So we could
easily change that to six sessions
divided between the preparatory and
integrative. I don't think that's an
issue. Um and this doesn't actually
limit um how many treatments that
someone can go through um with this.
This would just be per uh that set of
administration is what we are just
looking at. So uh agreement because they
could be that somebody has to go through
the treatment more than once. So,
>> and Jeff, Senator Steinborn,
>> is there anyone else on the list that
can go in front of me or not? I'll I'll
say piece real quick.
>> No, go ahead.
>> Okay, just real quick. Um, Dominic, um,
I guess what I'm worried about, be a
broken record, is what happens just if
if a practitioner in Albuquerque were to
suddenly submit to the department,
here's 100 patients that qualify. We'd
like to get them all funded.
You know, there will be some with the
sophistication level to be able to do
that. What can we build into the rules
that could just protect a run on the
fund? That would be a challenge a
thought request. What do you think?
>> Right. Thank Thank you, Senator. So the
the patients would still have to meet
all the qualifications for it and it is
a reimbursement. So there would not be a
guarantee of reimbursement and uh in
those kinds of cases. It's not unusual
and it is actually the usual situation
where the department puts in where we
have the ability to audit uh the patient
records to be able to ensure that the
treatments did happen. um and uh and
that they're not committing fraud
basically. And so those would be a part
of the usual aspects of it. Um
>> but let me ask you this. When you say a
reimbursement, do you mean the patient
would have to pay and they'd get
reimbursement or a clinic would be able
to get this voucher as you were to cover
their payment?
>> It would be the clinics would have to
submit for reimbursement.
>> Okay. So they would be they would be
getting paid after after after the fact
and they couldn't
>> correct.
>> Okay. Well, thank you Dominic. I would
just put that out there. You know how we
avoid a run on a run on the fund.
>> Yeah. But
>> yeah, and that would that would
definitely be a part and we would
include that in there. So what we could
actually include in here as part of the
recommendation is you know um to um uh
to have um audit um and um uh you know
to have audit um procedures uh to ensure
for that that there's not fraud being
conducted.
>> Yeah. And I don't even mean fraud. I
mean, just, you know, just some savvy
person just doing their doing a great
job really to just do it. And I'm I'm
throwing out, you know, just a scenario
hopefully won't happen.
>> But, uh, if it were, what power would
you have to say no? I mean, if the rule
says someone's qualified and they're
first in that door,
what's, you know, just the name? So
anytime that we have issue or we have
rules that are covering funds, they
always include uh the um the provision
that is um you know at the discretion of
the department and up until uh there is
no more funds. So um
>> so maybe you could maybe you could have
in language that just gave the
department the discretion
um to ensure the intent of the funds.
You know, uh, the department shall
retain the discretion to
[clears throat]
>> to modify to ensure the intent of the
fund and its geographic
u medicinal reach of the program.
Meaning, you know, statewide,
different conditions, different types of
practitioners maybe, you know what I'm
saying? So that way you could hit the
brakes if it was just a run on one area.
So anyway, thank you.
Just that otherwise I love what you've
come up with. I think it's perfect
personally.
>> Thank you.
>> Next.
>> Thank you, Senator. Um Ian,
>> hi. Yes. Um,
so
what is
um is this fund restricted to New Mexico
residents or could let's say uh
in a healing center opens up in Sunland
Park and we have a flood from El Paso
residents, would this fund be
um completely taken up by them or is it
exclusive? ly residents.
>> I would think that that would be part of
our recommendation,
but um I mean that's kind of I think
what I'm thinking is that you know it's
if we decide that it is restricted and
or if there already is a restriction in
there in the language for the fund
itself. Um, but I think that that if
it's not already, which I don't think
so, and Senator or Dominic can speak on
that, but I think that that would be a
recommendation from the committee to
recommend to the Department of Health
that it is restricted to New Mexico
residents only.
Dominic, did you want to add to that?
[laughter]
>> Oh, sorry. I had muted my mic. I was
actually speaking and it not coming
through. Um, yes, the I have already
added that into it as far as must be a
New Mexico resident. Um, and just a real
quick question, Chris, you can just uh
give me a thumbs up if I've got it
right. Is you're saying um six of the
combination preparatory integration
sessions and then up to three of the
administration days. Am I correct on
that? Or did you mean up to two
administration days? If you meant three,
just if you want to give me a thumbs up,
that's good. say so.
Yep. Three. Okay, perfect. Um, so yeah,
so I do have that and then I did add in
about um that the department would have
audit procedures to ensure there is
equity and appropriate use. Um, and that
ensure clauses within the regulations to
allow for the ability for the department
to hold or suspend payments out of the
fund.
All
right, I think that's um Go ahead.
>> Oh, no. I was going to say any other
additions, changes. By the way, these
are all really great and some of them
have been brought up before. I just as I
was putting this into the chat, I
neglected to put uh about the New Mexico
residency. So,
>> I think that's great. So far, um, we can
do like an official, um, so doing some
stupid math, throwing that as a
disclaimer first, you know, based on
what it is, I was just trying to come up
with, you know, a um $230
for a visit to a therapist per session.
Like just kind of throwing it out there.
Um, $350 for like the administration
session.
um two of them just kind of very this is
just very loose. It's not anything
particularly
um I rounded it out to about 3,500 based
on just whatever it is that Dominic had
there and that's about 180 people. So
just kind of for frame of reference if
everything based on what we had there
travel costs administration I know we
just changed it a little bit. I think I
had it at eight sessions total. um just
very roughly at like two around the
ballpark of $230 per therapist
um for an hour session. And of course,
this is going to the journey is going to
take a lot longer. So that would be
something completely different. And
that's not anything that's 180 people.
So, I'm just trying to kind of throw
that out there just so that people are
not like surprised about
um you know the
number um and it could be less
um because we haven't we don't know all
the variables but I was just basing it
off of a a a therapist session at $230.
>> So, yes, that is very that was good
math. Um, but I think where this program
gets interesting is in the research that
um, Larry Leman and others are working
on in terms of group sessions because
yes, it's $230 per hour with a
therapist. But if you have four PA or
eight patients under their supervision,
right, and two facilitators,
that lowers the cost significantly. So,
I think maybe 3500 is the highest if you
are uh in, you know, alone. You wanted a
one-on-one with the therapist while
because there are going to be people out
there that want to have them be the
person sitting with them. There are also
going to be people that want them 6 feet
away, closed door, don't talk to me. So
um I think both are possible but I think
that that is definitely the higher end
of what we would expect in this program.
Maybe while we are going to um go into
it.
>> Yeah. And and just to kind of point out,
Chris mentioned it in the chat and I
think I remember this from Hanifeh's um
presentation as well that it that the
variable for the group therapy doesn't
quite change it terribly too too much,
but it might change it in, you know, in
a different way. And again, just just
disclaimer, I was just throwing out
there so that we're not thinking, you
know, we're going to be, you know,
treating thousands of New Mexicans. It
would be wonderful. But just to be very
very have a very sober moment of
realizing that this is why this is so
special essentially you know like even
if we to me even if we were to able to
get like five people 10 people 20 people
that's not a whole lot of people. But
just think about it, you know, in terms
of like the philosophy, you know, that
you know, that one person that was able
to have this um, you know, go through
this program and to, you know, hopefully
be able to get something from it, to
have their life changed, I think that
that program and for us to be able to
make that that first person who's
involved is so completely totally worth
it. and that person having that ability
to get um something out of it and for
their community to be able to have that
person back online is amazing.
>> [snorts]
>> make that two people, five people, 10
people, 20 and if we can get like a
hundred all across New Mexico and we
have like this information and the
research and the data that we have been
able to say and to kind of come out of
it our SWAT assessment afterwards to say
that this is what we were able to do not
only for the individual person but for
the communities in as a whole and as you
know gathering to to together as a
collective to be able to support our own
people in this way I think is amazing.
So while and so people may not seem like
it's a lot I am hopeful that that we are
able to reach those 100 people and God
willing that they'll be able to have you
know a successful treatment that they
can continue on in their life and move
forward and that the rest of their
community is affected as well. So, it's
not just a matter of like, okay, we're
not, you know, $630,000. Yeah, I'm I'm
saying it's not a lot, but it is. Um,
but we are are hopefully being able to
bring our community back together um
through this fund in that way.
Um, all right. Any other things?
Dominic, do you wanted to say something?
>> Yeah. So, it seems like there's a lot of
consensus around here. Is it possible
to,
you know, to to see if this
recommendation would be something that
we should continue to move forward with?
>> Yes, thank you for reminding me. Um, if
anyone has just like a minute to go
ahead or I'll I'll read it out a little
bit, but um what we have here that uh
Dominic put into the chat is potential
recommendations. And if we wanted to
vote together to move this forward back
to the department of health for
recommend or to the uh advisory board a
potential recommendation cover for
individuals at or below 200% of the
poverty level items that would be
covered are diagnostic evaluation up to
six preparatory and or integrative
sessions, administration day up to three
administrations, cost of the medication,
travel if patient resides more than 100
miles from the appointment location or
healing center. Uh the fund would be
would be the last payer the equity fund
would be the last payer for example
would be or that is would be required to
attempt to get paid by the insurance
Medicaid etc first. So um I understand
that reimbursement not to exceed rates
for Medicaid reimbursement. Um that's a
safeguard department would have audit
procedures to ensure that there is
equity and appropriate use which is uh
to uh Senator Steinborn's concern about
rural rural um access
um to ensure clauses to allow for the
ability for the department to hold or
suspend payment out of the fund. And
this was tied back into the audit
process. Um, as depending on, you know,
if there seems something a little bit
suspicious, then they have the ability
to make a hold on that. Um, again, so
that this would be more equitable to
those. And last of all, must be a New
Mexico resident.
I will make a question on the 100 miles
though.
Um,
I don't know if it would be better to
have less. I'm not sure. Um, seeing as
that I think it's like 39 miles to
Albuquerque for me from Santa Fe and
that's can still be a problem for some
people I think. Um, but uh Chris, did
you want to say something?
Yeah, I mentioned it higher up in the
chat and I'm not sure who agreed with me
with the cover six non-admin sessions
per administration session. I think
that's a little too much but maybe two
additional ones per administration
um would be my recommendation.
>> So increasing the number from six to
eight. No. So it would be up to 10 if
they had two additional administrations
sessions.
>> Uh, gotcha, Chris, I misunderstood what
you meant. So you meant up to six
sessions if they had one administration
day, but add an additional two sessions
for each administration day up to three
administration days.
>> Up to two ad Okay, so up to three
administration days. Yes. And it would
be a total of my recommendation up to 10
nonadministration
days assuming they got all three
administrations.
Did I say that in a way that is
>> well so what what I'm just trying to
figure out. So if an individual just has
one administration day up to six
non-administration day sessions and then
if they have an additional one we add
two more. So then it goes up to eight.
If they do three administrations, then
it's up to 10.
>> Yeah. And I I don't think that it we
could write it in a way that maybe
they're not all necessary. So it's not
written in a way where they have to do
10 sessions, you know, but that'll give
them plenty of preparation and
integration, I think, to to help them
kind of take this into life. So
>> yeah. No, I think that sounds fine. Um
it just didn't come through in what you
had put in the uh the chat. So, uh, I'm
making an addendum on that part. So,
>> and, um, thank you, Chris, um, and
Dominic. And so, just I just did the
from my from where I'm at to Kiwa PBLO,
say for instance, um, from Kiwa to Santa
Fe is, uh, 28 miles just for frame of
reference as far as, you know, where
people may be traveling from. And so 100
seems a little excessive to me, but um I
just know that even some people have a
hard time to get from say a sovereign
nation in Kiwa to say like a local place
in Santa Fe. Um Greg, you had your hand
up.
>> Okay.
Um fully uh support what Chris is
saying. I think this is especially
valuable in SUDD cases. Um the more
flexibility we have on the practitioner
to move those around as needed
um will be very
uh yeah helpful [clears throat] on the
distance.
Perhaps we could leave it at 100 or 50
and then have a special hardship
application where somebody who may be
far off a road and not have a car can
make an application for special
con like a special case.
>> All right. Thank you, Greg and Ian.
Hi. Yes. Um, I just wanted to clarify
the miles are driving miles or crowsi
miles cuz those are
very different distances. I live in a
very hilly part of New Mexico. So,
>> yeah, it it's always travel is always
based on the travel distance. So, not
necessarily straight as the crow flies.
So,
Okay. All right. Any other
discussion?
Okay. I do, you know, I'm not my
illustration from the miles is just, you
know, to kind of put it out there. Um,
okay. Should we go ahead and agree that
with the included addendum which is if
needing more than one administration day
up to three administration days with an
additional two preparatory integrative
sessions for each additional
administration day. Um hopefully
everyone understood what that is. So if
you have one at five I think or six and
then two at 8 two administration days.
So it kind of increases as the number of
um administration days the integr um the
the integrative preparatory days
increases with the number of
administration days of the psilocybin.
Um all right. Does anybody have any more
discussion on this? Can we vote to say
that we're going to recommend this to
have as part of like the board? Um any
please raise your hand.
Okay, looks like we have five people.
All right.
Okay.
Okie do. All right. So, we will be
discussing this um with the rest of our
advisory board at our next advisory
meeting um and for more discussion on
that. Um I'm grateful for the advisory
um board members who are here to um
partake in this conversation and thank
you all for um you know your
>> just in case do you want to call the no
votes?
>> Yeah, sure. Does anybody not agree with
this?
>> Raise your hand please.
Going once. Going twice. Okay.
>> Well, just for the record.
>> Yes, for the record, there are no no
votes.
There are zero no votes. Okay. Well,
thank you all for that. Um,
okay.
I'm pretty much
done at this point unless there's
anything else anyone wants to have a
discussion on or ask any kinds of
questions or feels like we need to kind
of
move on to the next um Dominic or Ian
Chris Senator Seinborn anybody else
Greg? So despa I mean we don't have
anything else on our side but just so
that you know what we will do um from
the program is we will get this
recommendation written up so you don't
need to worry about that and then you'll
have that for the next board meeting.
>> Okay. And hopefully when um when we all
come back together again um we'll have
the tribal sovereignty presentation from
Marina Robbins. Some of you already know
her. Um she's an amazing person who is
working from University of California,
Berkeley in her PhD program. Um Greg,
yes.
>> Uh just to confirm that will be written
in rules form, not recommendation.
Correct.
>> I think that this will
well since it's kind of coming from
[laughter] Department of Health.
>> Yeah. Yeah. That's a dong dong question.
Yeah.
>> Yep. Until the the board says that yay
or nay on it, it'll be in the
recommendation form, but we may
depending uh exactly how much time we're
able to put towards it. We may have it
more in a rule form. As many of you
know, we try to do that when we can, but
it may not all be in. So, I just don't
want to promise something uh and not be
able to deliver that. So, we'll do the
best we can, but you know, we'll I'll
reserve the right to not not tax
[laughter] the staff too much if that's
okay with everyone.
>> But in a perfect in a perfect world, it
will be prepped and ready to go into the
same hearing that training and education
will go into. Correct.
>> Uh it won't go into that same hearing.
It'll take us longer than that. Um and
we'll need to do it with the board. Uh
mostly because it you have to submit
things for publication. And there's lots
of other aspects to it that that are
more and outside of just these meetings
and the board meeting, but we're going
to try to move it as quickly as we can
simply so that we have the equity fund
in place and ready for when patients are
going to be seen.
>> Yes. And to just reiterate for anybody,
so essentially what has already been
written in the chat is in plain language
will be sent to and discussed at our
next board meeting, I believe September
11th, and we'll have more discussion
there. And the language that we have on
the chat may or may not be changed
somewhat so that it's more of a legal
ease essentially. Um, but as Dominic
said, you know, everybody's busy doing a
million different things back there. Um,
[laughter] so it may or may not change
from this, but either way, it will just
be more legal as opposed to plain
language that we have here. Um,
because as everybody remembers from uh,
Schoolhouse Rocks, I'm just a bill. This
not this is a bill, but there's a
process for that for this recommendation
to go through. So, this is the
committee. It's going to go to the
psilocybin board September 11th from the
psilocybin board. We're going to then
make it an official recommendation from
the board to then pass it back to the
department of health. Um right now the
department of health is just graciously
being able to like put all of this
together um for us here. Um any other
last minute thoughts,
ideas?
Um,
I thank you all for everything that you
have, uh, you know, thought about. I
know that this has just been kind of
hard and difficult to kind of figure out
like, yeah, this is just, um, a lot of
figuring out who who who's going to get
what. Uh, yes, Greg.
Just something to think about as we go
into the reality of this. If HCA is
delayed till fiscal year 2028
on
payments for
Medicaid,
the impact that that delay will have on
the on the equity fund could be massive.
Whereas if they with if there's an
alignment in program roll out with HCA
payment cap capacity
then the equity fund would go a lot
further. So I think that's not something
that we can solve today just something
that um was on my mind that we might
want to watch.
>> Yeah. And I think that you know what
you're pointing out something a little
bit that we're kind of coming out and
this is why I did this loose math
essentially was you know if everything
was paid for at least that's what it
sounds like here and we can probably
have I think we all want to go but you
know um if everything was paid for
through this equity fund all of the
sessions as we had stated it here with
three administration days up to 10
preparatory integration days plus travel
plus the administration of the of the
medicine um and all these other things.
That was where that loose math kind of
came from capped at like $3,500.
It could be more, but if we were just to
look at $3,500 for a whole session for
like one
one treatment for one person and we we
were saying that it was like $3,500
roughly, that's 180 people. Now, what I
from what I hear you're saying is that
if we if we do kick in the HCA
and anything else that will just
increase the number of people we could
potentially
treat.
That is to say also too depending on the
other variables which is how much a
session actually is going to be. How
much is the medication of the medicine
going to be? And I think the numbers
that I was using, if you guys want to go
home and think about it yourselves, is
like I was just kind of moving it at
$230 per session.
Um I think with the number of sessions
that we increased it to brings it down
to about a 100 people. Um but $230 per
treatment session, maybe $ 350 on the
day of, but we also have like an eight
hour um up to like eight hours for a
journey. So, that person's going to be
there. Are they billing at $230 for each
hour? Um, and that sort of thing. So,
yeah, it will it will increase the cost
if we have other people um applying, but
you know, there's a potential of
reaching at least 100 people at least
from the loose math. So, anyways, thank
you all for being here. I really
appreciate it. um grateful for your
time, presence and um for all the good
work that you are doing in your own
places. So have a great afternoon
>> and on behalf of the department, thank
you everybody. Have a great afternoon
and week. Thank you Despa.